Hey, what's up everyone?
こんにちは、みんな元気？
Are you ready to get a new superpower in English? Seriously.
英語で新しいスーパーパワーを手に入れる準備はできてる？本気で。
Today, we're going to learn how to give commands, you know, the kind of stuff you hear all the
今日は命令の言い方を学ぶよ。映画やゲームでよく聞くやつね。
time in movies and video games. So let's do this. Let's power up.
さあ、始めよう。パワーアップだ。
So how do you say stuff like do this or look in English?
「これをやれ」や「見ろ」は英語でどう言うの？
You hear it all the time, right?
よく聞くよね？
Like in an action movie when the hero yells go or in a video game when your teammate
アクション映画でヒーローが「行け！」って叫んだり、ゲームで仲間が「気をつけろ！」って叫んだり。
shouts look out.
それが命令だよ。
Well those are commands and today we're going to figure out exactly how to use
今日はその使い方を学んで、自然に聞こえるようにしよう。
them so you can sound super natural.
まずは「ボス命令」をマスターしよう。
Okay, first up, let's master what I like to call the boss command.
これは直接的でシンプルな指示を出すための基本的なパワーアップだよ。
This is your basic Level 1 power-up for giving direct, simple instructions.
チームキャプテンやゲームの主人公が仲間に指示を出すようなもの。
You know, just like a team captain or the main character in a game telling their squad
ルールはとてもシンプルなんだ。
exactly what to do. And get this, the rule is so, so simple.
主語の「私」や「あなた」を一瞬忘れて。
You just forget about subjects like I or you for a second.
文の最初に動詞を基本形で始めるだけ。
All you have to do is start your sentence with the main action word, the verb, in
辞書に載っている形だよ。
its basic original form, like the form you'd find in a dictionary.
ingやsは不要。動詞そのものだけ。
No ing, no s's at the end, nothing extra. Just the verb itself.
このシンプルなルールはすべてに適用できるよ。
And check this out. This one simple rule works for everything.
普通の動詞なら「来て」や「立って」だね。
For regular action verbs, what you might call a ipandoshi, it's just, come here.
でもb動詞はどうなる？
Or stand up. Easy. But what about the b-verb? Or b-doshi?
am、is、areは使わないよ。
Well, you don't use am, is, or are. Nope.
基本形の「be」を使うだけ。「静かにして」。
You just use its original base form, b. So you get, be quiet.
「気をつけて」。ほら、すごく簡単でしょ？
Be careful. See? Super simple, right? Alright, time for a quick quiz.
さあ、クイズをやってみよう。
Let's test this out.
試してみよう。
Imagine your friend is walking and they don't see something on the floor.
友達が歩いていて、床のものに気づかないとする。
They're about to trip. What do you yell?
つまずきそうな時、何て叫ぶ？
Is it am careful, be careful, or is careful?
「am careful」「be careful」「is careful」のどれ？
Think back to that rule we just talked about, the base form.
さっきの基本形のルールを思い出して。
And the answer is be careful. Yes, you got it.
答えは「be careful」。その通り。
For commands, you always, always use that base form, B, awesome job.
命令では、常に基本形の「be」を使うんだ。素晴らしい！
Okay, so the boss command is super useful, for sure.
ボス命令はとても便利だね。
But let's be real, it can sometimes sound a little, well, bossy.
でも、時にはちょっと「上から目線」に聞こえることもある。
So now it's time to level up our skill and add a politeness boost.
だから、スキルをレベルアップして、丁寧さを加えよう。
And all it takes is one simple magic word.
それには一つの魔法の言葉が必要。
You guessed it, that magic word is please.
その魔法の言葉は「please」。
Now you've got two options here.
ここで二つの選択肢がある。
You can stick it right at the beginning of the sentence.
文の最初に置くか。
Please sit down or you can pop it on the end
「Please sit down」か、文の最後に置くか。
But and this is a super important if if you put it at the end you've got to add a little comma right before it
でも、最後に置く場合は、前に小さなカンマを入れることが大事。
So it's sit down, please. It seems like a tiny detail, but trust me. It makes all the difference
「sit down, please」。小さなポイントだけど、信じて。大きな違いがあるよ。
Okay, fantastic. So you know how to tell people what to do, but what about telling them what not to do?
素晴らしい！人に何をするか伝えられるようになったけど、何をしないかはどう？
Sometimes that's even more important, right?
それも時には重要だよね？
For that, you need the stop command. Think of it as your defensive superpower.
それには「stop command」が必要。防御のスーパーパワーだと思って。
The secret weapon for this command is one simple powerful word. Are you ready? It's don't.
この命令の秘密の武器は、シンプルで強力な言葉。準備はいい？それは「don't」。
And guess what? The rule here is just as easy as before. You literally just put don't at the
ルールも前と同じくらい簡単。文の最初に「don't」を置くだけ。
very beginning of the sentence right before that same base verb we've been using. That's
その後に同じ基本動詞を続けるだけ。それで終わり。
That's it. You're done. And you can see, this works for everything.
これもすべてに適用できるよ。
In the hallway at school, don't run.
学校の廊下では「don't run」。
In the movie theater, don't use your cell phone here.
映画館では「don't use your cell phone here」。
And yeah, of course it works perfectly with the B-verb too.
もちろん、b動詞にも完璧に使えるよ。
In the library, a sign might say, don't be noisy.
図書館では「don't be noisy」と書かれているかも。
And what does your teacher always say? Don't be late. See?
先生がいつも言うのは「don't be late」。ほら、シンプルなルールで全部カバーできる。
One simple rule covers them all.
さあ、命令を出すのはここまで。
Alright, enough with now giving orders and telling people what to do.
人に何をするか言うのは、いつも楽しいわけじゃないよね？
I mean, that's not always fun, right?
じゃあ、友達と一緒に何かを提案したい時は？
So, what if you want to suggest doing something together with your friends?
そのためには、究極のチームアップフレーズが必要。
For that, we need the ultimate team-up phrase.
誰かを楽しみに誘うには、「let's」が魔法の言葉。
So to invite someone to join in on the fun, the magic word is let's.
「let us」の短くてクールな言い方なんだ。
And the rule is, well, you can probably guess it by now.
ルールは、もう分かると思います。
You just start the sentence with let's and follow it with yep, the base form of the
文を「let's」で始めて、動詞の原形を続けます。
verb.
はい。
Okay, so maybe the school festival is coming up and a great song comes on.
例えば、学校祭が近づいて素敵な曲が流れたら、
You can turn to your friends and say, let's dance!
友達に「let's dance!」と言えます。
the lunch bell finally rings and your stomach is rumbling. What do you say? Let's eat lunch.
昼のチャイムが鳴ってお腹が鳴ったら、「let's eat lunch.」と言います。
And when that final bell rings at the end of the day, let's play basketball after school.
そして、学校の終わりにチャイムが鳴ったら、「let's play basketball after school.」です。
It's just the perfect, most natural way to make plans with your friends.
友達と計画を立てるのに最適な方法です。
And hey, check it out. This also works perfectly with the verb be. If you're in the library,
これ、動詞「be」とも完璧に使えます。図書館にいるとき、
you and your friends might whisper, let's be quiet. Or if you're doing a tricky science
友達と「let's be quiet.」とささやくこともできます。
experiment, you'd say, let's be careful. It's the best way to agree on how everyone in the
難しい科学実験をしているときは、「let's be careful.」と言います。
than the group should act. You can even say, let's be friends.
みんながどう行動するかを合意するのに最適です。「let's be friends.」とも言えます。
Okay, so you've unlocked the boss command,
さて、ボスコマンドを解放しました。
the stop command and the team-up phrase. You've got all the power-ups,
ストップコマンドとチームアップフレーズも手に入れました。
but I saved the biggest, most amazing secret for last.
でも、最後に一番大きな秘密を教えます。
This is something that explains why all of these commands
これが、なぜこれらのコマンドが
are so unique and so special. Okay, I want you to look really closely
特別でユニークなのかを説明します。シンプルなコマンド文をよく見てください。
at a simple command sentence. Just stand up.
「Just stand up.」です。
Now think about it for a second.
少し考えてみてください。
what part of a normal English sentence seems to be missing.
普通の英語の文のどの部分が欠けているでしょうか。
I'm sure your English teacher has told you this a million times.
英語の先生が何度も言ったことがあると思います。
Every English sentence needs a subject and a verb, right?
英語の文には主語と動詞が必要ですよね？
Like I study or she plays tennis.
例えば「I study」や「she plays tennis」です。
But in stand up, we've only got the verb stand.
でも「stand up」には動詞「stand」しかありません。
So where in the world is the subject? And here it is, the big reveal,
じゃあ、主語はどこにあるのでしょう？ここにあります、大発表です。
the secret subject is you. That's right, the subject is there,
秘密の主語は「you」です。そう、主語は存在しますが、
but it's invisible. In every single command sentence,
見えないのです。すべてのコマンド文では、
the subject is always automatically the person you're talking to, you.
主語は常に話している相手、つまり「you」です。
So when you say stand up,
だから「stand up」と言うと、
what your brain is really saying is you stand up. Kinda cool, right?
脳が言っているのは「you stand up」です。面白いですよね？
And that is what makes these sentences so powerful and so special.
これが、これらの文を強力で特別なものにしています。
They don't even need to say the word you
「you」という言葉を言わなくても、
because it's already built right in. This makes commands the fastest,
すでに組み込まれています。これにより、コマンドは
most direct way to communicate with someone.
最も迅速で直接的なコミュニケーション方法です。
It's like a direct line to the person you're talking to.
話している相手に直接つながるようなものです。
So there you have it. Your command power- up is complete.
これで、あなたのコマンドパワーアップは完了です。
You can now give clear directions, make polite requests,
明確な指示を出したり、丁寧なリクエストをしたり、
warn a friend, and make awesome plans together.
友達に警告したり、一緒に素晴らしい計画を立てたりできます。
It's a real communication superpower. So my final question for you is,
本当にコミュニケーションのスーパーパワーです。最後の質問です。
now that you have it, how are you gonna use it?
これを手に入れた今、どう使いますか？